Erica C. Bohler

Hayward, CA • Phone: 404-217-9577 • E-Mail: ericac.moore@gmail.com

Summary

Senior Project Controls Engineer with 8+ years of construction management and project controls experience seeking a continued project controls leadership role, assisting with earned-value measurement, project planning, cost estimation and management and overall budget control.

Skills

- Construction Management
- Personnel Selection
- Performance Management
- Change Control
- Earned-Value Measurement

- Project Planning
- Contract
 Management/Negotiation/Design
- · Cost Estimation and Management
- Project Control

- Process Scheduler
- Vendor and Contractor Communication

Experience

Bechtel Corporation, San Francisco, CA

October 2012 - Present

Senior Cost Engineer

- Managed cost estimates, schedule/budget oversight and financial project closeout of 180 projects estimated at \$16 million
- Analyzed earned-value and cost trends for the NSB project.
- Performed scheduling and planning for 180 projects for engineering, site acquisition and construction

Bechtel Corporation, Montvale, NJ

June 2010 - October 2012

Scope Manager

- Responsible for 600+ projects estimated at \$30 million with a team of 15 members including field construction managers, safety personnel, architects/engineers, etc.
- Managed and tracked all milestones/activities for engineering, site acquisition and construction from design and execution through completion and turnover; organized and held readiness reviews
- · Assisted with all construction coordination activities such as overseeing construction manager/general contractor activities

Bechtel Corporation, Houston, TX

January 2010 - June 2010

Lead Field Engineer

- Gathered, organized and disseminated specs and requirements from design to field operations
- Assisted in developing quality metrics to improve overall construction quality
- Responsible for ES&H training/education, incident reports and investigations and implement standard ES&H policies and procedures

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology - B.S. in Electrical Engineering

May 2006

Spelman College - B.S. in Computer Science

May 2006